<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<doxygen xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="compound.xsd" version="1.7.6.1">
  <compounddef id="indexpage" kind="page">
    <compoundname>index</compoundname>
    <title>A Gui designed to simplify the creation of Amiga configuration file</title>
    <detaileddescription>
<sect1 id="index_1UAE">
<title>&quot;There are several options available to tune your Amiga experience.&quot;</title>
<para>Unix <ref refid="d1/d60/classAmiga" kindref="compound">Amiga</ref> Emulator (UAE) is a software emulator of the <ref refid="d1/d60/classAmiga" kindref="compound">Amiga</ref> platform that runs on Unix machines.<linebreak/>
 Its purpose is to reproduce the hardware of the original system, so that software written for the emulated machine &quot;does not notice&quot; the difference between the real and the virtual machine created by the emulator, and then &quot;turns&quot; just like on the original system. </para><sect2 id="index_1AmigaDOS">
<title>AmigaDOS Beer: a brief &quot;story&quot; of Amiga.</title>
<para>The company has gone out of business, but their recipe has been picked up by some weird German company, so now this beer will be an import. This beer never really sold very well because the original manufacturer didn’t understand marketing. Like Unix Beer, AmigaDOS Beer fans are an extremely loyal and loud group. It originally came in a 16-oz. can, but now comes in 32-oz. cans too. When this can was originally introduced, it appeared flashy and colorful, but the design hasn’t changed much over the years, so it appears dated now. Critics of this beer claim that it is only meant for watching TV anyway. </para></sect2>
<sect2 id="index_1Hardware">
<title>Hradware</title>
<para>The <ref refid="d1/d60/classAmiga" kindref="compound">Amiga</ref> hardware characteristic is the Motorola 68000 processor flanked by three custom-built chips that are designed to alleviate the workload of the processor: Agnus, Denise and Paula. </para><sect3 id="index_1Agnus">
<title>Agnus:</title>
<para>Agnus performs three functions:<linebreak/>
 </para></sect3>
</sect2>
<sect2 id="index_1Denise">
<title>Denise:</title>
<para>Denise is the chip that deals with the generation of the video output.<linebreak/>
 Denise displays up to 64 colors (at most 6 bits per pixel indicating the color to be used, among those in the registers of color), from a palette of 4096 (12 bit, ie 4 for each color component R, G and B, for each color register). Through mode called HAM (short for Hold And Modify) can simultaneously show 4096 colors.<linebreak/>
 Another function of the chip Denise is the management of the sprite, graphic objects of limited size (16 pixels wide and up to 255 high), completely independent resolution and number of colors from the screen below (called &quot;playfield&quot;), and which is the same hardware to implement the display and movement. Denise handles up to eight sprites to four colors; they can then be combined to obtain moving objects larger and with a greater number of colors; in the same frame a sprite can be reused several times, on the condition that between two copies is maintained distance of a video line horizontal.<linebreak/>
 </para><sect3 id="index_1Paula">
<title>Paula:</title>
<para>Paula is the sound chip, which manages four entries digital 8-bit <ref refid="d1/d60/classAmiga" kindref="compound">Amiga</ref>.<linebreak/>
 <ref refid="d1/d60/classAmiga" kindref="compound">Amiga</ref> produces stereo sound: two items are associated audio to the right channel, and two to the left channel, all items are independent, then the two channels from sounds completely different.<linebreak/>
 Paula is also responsible for the management of floppy-disk driver and port I/O: the parallel port &quot;Centronics&quot; and the RS-232 25-pin.<linebreak/>
 </para></sect3>
</sect2>
</sect1>
    </detaileddescription>
  </compounddef>
</doxygen>
